<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<functions>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>absLong</name>
    <description>Returns the absolute value of a long value. If the argument is not negative, the argument is returned. If the argument is negative, the negation of the argument is returned.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>long abs(long)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>absDouble</name>
    <description>Returns the absolute value of a double value. If the argument is not negative, the argument is returned. If the argument is negative, the negation of the argument is returned. Special cases:

        If the argument is positive zero or negative zero, the result is positive zero.
        If the argument is infinite, the result is positive infinity.
        If the argument is NaN, the result is NaN.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double abs(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>absFloat</name>
    <description>Returns the absolute value of a float value. If the argument is not negative, the argument is returned. If the argument is negative, the negation of the argument is returned. Special cases:

        If the argument is positive zero or negative zero, the result is positive zero.
        If the argument is infinite, the result is positive infinity.
        If the argument is NaN, the result is NaN.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>float abs(float)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>absInteger</name>
    <description>Returns the absolute value of an int value. If the argument is not negative, the argument is returned. If the argument is negative, the negation of the argument is returned
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>int abs(int)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>sin</name>
    <description>Returns the trigonometric sine of an angle. Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN or an infinity, then the result is NaN.
        If the argument is zero, then the result is a zero with the same sign as the argument.

    A result must be within 1 ulp of the correctly rounded result. Results must be semi-monotonic.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double sin(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>cos</name>
    <description>Returns the trigonometric cosine of an angle. Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN or an infinity, then the result is NaN.

    A result must be within 1 ulp of the correctly rounded result. Results must be semi-monotonic.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double cos(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>tan</name>
    <description>Returns the trigonometric tangent of an angle. Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN or an infinity, then the result is NaN.
        If the argument is zero, then the result is a zero with the same sign as the argument.

    A result must be within 1 ulp of the correctly rounded result. Results must be semi-monotonic.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double tan(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>atan2</name>
    <description>Converts rectangular coordinates (x, y) to polar (r, theta). This method computes the phase theta by computing an arc tangent of y/x in the range of -pi to pi. Special cases:

        If either argument is NaN, then the result is NaN.
        If the first argument is positive zero and the second argument is positive, or the first argument is positive and finite and the second argument is positive infinity, then the result is positive zero.
        If the first argument is negative zero and the second argument is positive, or the first argument is negative and finite and the second argument is positive infinity, then the result is negative zero.
        If the first argument is positive zero and the second argument is negative, or the first argument is positive and finite and the second argument is negative infinity, then the result is the double value closest to pi.
        If the first argument is negative zero and the second argument is negative, or the first argument is negative and finite and the second argument is negative infinity, then the result is the double value closest to -pi.
        If the first argument is positive and the second argument is positive zero or negative zero, or the first argument is positive infinity and the second argument is finite, then the result is the double value closest to pi/2.
        If the first argument is negative and the second argument is positive zero or negative zero, or the first argument is negative infinity and the second argument is finite, then the result is the double value closest to -pi/2.
        If both arguments are positive infinity, then the result is the double value closest to pi/4.
        If the first argument is positive infinity and the second argument is negative infinity, then the result is the double value closest to 3*pi/4.
        If the first argument is negative infinity and the second argument is positive infinity, then the result is the double value closest to -pi/4.
        If both arguments are negative infinity, then the result is the double value closest to -3*pi/4.

    A result must be within 2 ulps of the correctly rounded result. Results must be semi-monotonic.
	</description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double atan2(double,double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>sqrt</name>
    <description>Returns the correctly rounded positive square root of a double value. Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN or less than zero, then the result is NaN.
        If the argument is positive infinity, then the result is positive infinity.
        If the argument is positive zero or negative zero, then the result is the same as the argument.

    Otherwise, the result is the double value closest to the true mathematical square root of the argument value.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double sqrt(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>log</name>
    <description>Returns the natural logarithm (base e) of a double value. Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN or less than zero, then the result is NaN.
        If the argument is positive infinity, then the result is positive infinity.
        If the argument is positive zero or negative zero, then the result is negative infinity.

    A result must be within 1 ulp of the correctly rounded result. Results must be semi-monotonic.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double log(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>log10</name>
    <description>Returns the base 10 logarithm of a double value. Special cases:

    If the argument is NaN or less than zero, then the result is NaN.
    If the argument is positive infinity, then the result is positive infinity.
    If the argument is positive zero or negative zero, then the result is negative infinity.
    If the argument is equal to 10n for integer n, then the result is n. 

	The computed result must be within 1 ulp of the exact result. Results must be semi-monotonic.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double log10(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>pow</name>
    <description>Returns the value of the first argument raised to the power of the second argument. Special cases:

        If the second argument is positive or negative zero, then the result is 1.0.
        If the second argument is 1.0, then the result is the same as the first argument.
        If the second argument is NaN, then the result is NaN.
        If the first argument is NaN and the second argument is nonzero, then the result is NaN.
        If
            the absolute value of the first argument is greater than 1 and the second argument is positive infinity, or
            the absolute value of the first argument is less than 1 and the second argument is negative infinity, 
        then the result is positive infinity.
        If
            the absolute value of the first argument is greater than 1 and the second argument is negative infinity, or
            the absolute value of the first argument is less than 1 and the second argument is positive infinity, 
        then the result is positive zero.
        If the absolute value of the first argument equals 1 and the second argument is infinite, then the result is NaN.
        If
            the first argument is positive zero and the second argument is greater than zero, or
            the first argument is positive infinity and the second argument is less than zero, 
        then the result is positive zero.
        If
            the first argument is positive zero and the second argument is less than zero, or
            the first argument is positive infinity and the second argument is greater than zero, 
        then the result is positive infinity.
        If
            the first argument is negative zero and the second argument is greater than zero but not a finite odd integer, or
            the first argument is negative infinity and the second argument is less than zero but not a finite odd integer, 
        then the result is positive zero.
        If
            the first argument is negative zero and the second argument is a positive finite odd integer, or
            the first argument is negative infinity and the second argument is a negative finite odd integer, 
        then the result is negative zero.
        If
            the first argument is negative zero and the second argument is less than zero but not a finite odd integer, or
            the first argument is negative infinity and the second argument is greater than zero but not a finite odd integer, 
        then the result is positive infinity.
        If
            the first argument is negative zero and the second argument is a negative finite odd integer, or
            the first argument is negative infinity and the second argument is a positive finite odd integer, 
        then the result is negative infinity.
        If the first argument is finite and less than zero
            if the second argument is a finite even integer, the result is equal to the result of raising the absolute value of the first argument to the power of the second argument
            if the second argument is a finite odd integer, the result is equal to the negative of the result of raising the absolute value of the first argument to the power of the second argument
            if the second argument is finite and not an integer, then the result is NaN. 
        If both arguments are integers, then the result is exactly equal to the mathematical result of raising the first argument to the power of the second argument if that result can in fact be represented exactly as a double value.

    (In the foregoing descriptions, a floating-point value is considered to be an integer if and only if it is finite and a fixed point of the method ceil or, equivalently, a fixed point of the method floor. A value is a fixed point of a one-argument method if and only if the result of applying the method to the value is equal to the value.)

    The computed result must be within 1 ulp of the exact result. Results must be semi-monotonic.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double pow(double,double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>exp</name>
    <description>Returns Euler's number e raised to the power of a double value. Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN, the result is NaN.
        If the argument is positive infinity, then the result is positive infinity.
        If the argument is negative infinity, then the result is positive zero.

    The computed result must be within 1 ulp of the exact result. Results must be semi-monotonic.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double exp(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>minDouble</name>
    <description>Returns the smaller of two double values. That is, the result is the value closer to negative infinity. If the arguments have the same value, the result is that same value. If either value is NaN, then the result is NaN. Unlike the numerical comparison operators, this method considers negative zero to be strictly smaller than positive zero. If one argument is positive zero and the other is negative zero, the result is negative zero.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double min(double,double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>minFloat</name>
    <description>Returns the smaller of two float values. That is, the result is the value closer to negative infinity. If the arguments have the same value, the result is that same value. If either value is NaN, then the result is NaN. Unlike the numerical comparison operators, this method considers negative zero to be strictly smaller than positive zero. If one argument is positive zero and the other is negative zero, the result is negative zero.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>float min(float,float)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>minLong</name>
    <description>Returns the smaller of two long values. That is, the result is the argument closer to the value of Long.MIN_VALUE. If the arguments have the same value, the result is that same value.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>long min(long,long)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>minInteger</name>
    <description>Returns the smaller of two int values. That is, the result the argument closer to the value of Integer.MIN_VALUE. If the arguments have the same value, the result is that same value.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>int min(int,int)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>maxFloat</name>
    <description>Returns the greater of two float values. That is, the result is the argument closer to positive infinity. If the arguments have the same value, the result is that same value. If either value is NaN, then the result is NaN. Unlike the numerical comparison operators, this method considers negative zero to be strictly smaller than positive zero. If one argument is positive zero and the other negative zero, the result is positive zero.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>float max(float,float)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>maxLong</name>
    <description>Returns the greater of two long values. That is, the result is the argument closer to the value of Long.MAX_VALUE. If the arguments have the same value, the result is that same value.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>long max(long,long)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>maxInteger</name>
    <description>Returns the greater of two int values. That is, the result is the argument closer to the value of Integer.MAX_VALUE. If the arguments have the same value, the result is that same value.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>int max(int,int)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>maxDouble</name>
    <description>Returns the greater of two double values. That is, the result is the argument closer to positive infinity. If the arguments have the same value, the result is that same value. If either value is NaN, then the result is NaN. Unlike the numerical comparison operators, this method considers negative zero to be strictly smaller than positive zero. If one argument is positive zero and the other negative zero, the result is positive zero.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double max(double,double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>scalbFloat</name>
    <description>Return f × 2scaleFactor rounded as if performed by a single correctly rounded floating-point multiply to a member of the float value set. See the Java Language Specification for a discussion of floating-point value sets. If the exponent of the result is between Float.MIN_EXPONENT and Float.MAX_EXPONENT, the answer is calculated exactly. If the exponent of the result would be larger than Float.MAX_EXPONENT, an infinity is returned. Note that if the result is subnormal, precision may be lost; that is, when scalb(x, n) is subnormal, scalb(scalb(x, n), -n) may not equal x. When the result is non-NaN, the result has the same sign as f.

    Special cases:

        If the first argument is NaN, NaN is returned.
        If the first argument is infinite, then an infinity of the same sign is returned.
        If the first argument is zero, then a zero of the same sign is returned.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>float scalb(float,int)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>scalbDouble</name>
    <description>Return d × 2scaleFactor rounded as if performed by a single correctly rounded floating-point multiply to a member of the double value set. See the Java Language Specification for a discussion of floating-point value sets. If the exponent of the result is between Double.MIN_EXPONENT and Double.MAX_EXPONENT, the answer is calculated exactly. If the exponent of the result would be larger than Double.MAX_EXPONENT, an infinity is returned. Note that if the result is subnormal, precision may be lost; that is, when scalb(x, n) is subnormal, scalb(scalb(x, n), -n) may not equal x. When the result is non-NaN, the result has the same sign as d.

    Special cases:

        If the first argument is NaN, NaN is returned.
        If the first argument is infinite, then an infinity of the same sign is returned.
        If the first argument is zero, then a zero of the same sign is returned.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double scalb(double,int)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>getExponentDouble</name>
    <description>Returns the unbiased exponent used in the representation of a double. Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN or infinite, then the result is Double.MAX_EXPONENT + 1.
        If the argument is zero or subnormal, then the result is Double.MIN_EXPONENT -1.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>int getExponent(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>getExponentFloat</name>
    <description>Returns the unbiased exponent used in the representation of a float. Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN or infinite, then the result is Float.MAX_EXPONENT + 1.
        If the argument is zero or subnormal, then the result is Float.MIN_EXPONENT -1. 
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>int getExponent(float)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>signumFloat</name>
    <description>Returns the signum function of the argument; zero if the argument is zero, 1.0f if the argument is greater than zero, -1.0f if the argument is less than zero.

    Special Cases:

        If the argument is NaN, then the result is NaN.
        If the argument is positive zero or negative zero, then the result is the same as the argument. 
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>float signum(float)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>signumDouble</name>
    <description>Returns the signum function of the argument; zero if the argument is zero, 1.0 if the argument is greater than zero, -1.0 if the argument is less than zero.

    Special Cases:

        If the argument is NaN, then the result is NaN.
        If the argument is positive zero or negative zero, then the result is the same as the argument. 
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double signum(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>asin</name>
    <description>Returns the arc sine of a value; the returned angle is in the range -pi/2 through pi/2. Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN or its absolute value is greater than 1, then the result is NaN.
        If the argument is zero, then the result is a zero with the same sign as the argument.

    The computed result must be within 1 ulp of the exact result. Results must be semi-monotonic.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double asin(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>acos</name>
    <description>Returns the arc cosine of a value; the returned angle is in the range 0.0 through pi. Special case:

        If the argument is NaN or its absolute value is greater than 1, then the result is NaN.

    The computed result must be within 1 ulp of the exact result. Results must be semi-monotonic.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double acos(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>atan</name>
    <description>Returns the arc tangent of a value; the returned angle is in the range -pi/2 through pi/2. Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN, then the result is NaN.
        If the argument is zero, then the result is a zero with the same sign as the argument.

    The computed result must be within 1 ulp of the exact result. Results must be semi-monotonic.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double atan(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>toRadians</name>
    <description>Converts an angle measured in degrees to an approximately equivalent angle measured in radians. The conversion from degrees to radians is generally inexact.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double toRadians(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>toDegrees</name>
    <description>Converts an angle measured in radians to an approximately equivalent angle measured in degrees. The conversion from radians to degrees is generally inexact; users should not expect cos(toRadians(90.0)) to exactly equal 0.0.

    Parameters:
        angrad - an angle, in radians 
    Returns:
        the measurement of the angle angrad in degrees.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double toDegrees(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>cbrt</name>
    <description>Returns the cube root of a double value. For positive finite x, cbrt(-x) == -cbrt(x); that is, the cube root of a negative value is the negative of the cube root of that value's magnitude. Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN, then the result is NaN.
        If the argument is infinite, then the result is an infinity with the same sign as the argument.
        If the argument is zero, then the result is a zero with the same sign as the argument. 

    The computed result must be within 1 ulp of the exact result.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double cbrt(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>IEEEremainder</name>
    <description>Computes the remainder operation on two arguments as prescribed by the IEEE 754 standard. The remainder value is mathematically equal to f1 - f2 × n, where n is the mathematical integer closest to the exact mathematical value of the quotient f1/f2, and if two mathematical integers are equally close to f1/f2, then n is the integer that is even. If the remainder is zero, its sign is the same as the sign of the first argument. Special cases:

        If either argument is NaN, or the first argument is infinite, or the second argument is positive zero or negative zero, then the result is NaN.
        If the first argument is finite and the second argument is infinite, then the result is the same as the first argument.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double IEEEremainder(double,double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>ceil</name>
    <description>Returns the smallest (closest to negative infinity) double value that is greater than or equal to the argument and is equal to a mathematical integer. Special cases:

        If the argument value is already equal to a mathematical integer, then the result is the same as the argument.
        If the argument is NaN or an infinity or positive zero or negative zero, then the result is the same as the argument.
        If the argument value is less than zero but greater than -1.0, then the result is negative zero.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double ceil(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>floor</name>
    <description>Returns the largest (closest to positive infinity) double value that is less than or equal to the argument and is equal to a mathematical integer. Special cases:

        If the argument value is already equal to a mathematical integer, then the result is the same as the argument.
        If the argument is NaN or an infinity or positive zero or negative zero, then the result is the same as the argument.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double floor(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>rint</name>
    <description>Returns the double value that is closest in value to the argument and is equal to a mathematical integer. If two double values that are mathematical integers are equally close, the result is the integer value that is even. Special cases:

        If the argument value is already equal to a mathematical integer, then the result is the same as the argument.
        If the argument is NaN or an infinity or positive zero or negative zero, then the result is the same as the argument.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double rint(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>roundFloat</name>
    <description>Returns the closest int to the argument. The result is rounded to an integer by adding 1/2, taking the floor of the result, and casting the result to type int.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>int round(float)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>roundDouble</name>
    <description>Returns the closest long to the argument. The result is rounded to an integer by adding 1/2, taking the floor of the result, and casting the result to type long.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>long round(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <!--<function>-->
    <!--<prefix>math</prefix>-->
    <!--<name>random</name>-->
    <!--<function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>-->
    <!--<function-signature>double random()</function-signature>-->
  <!--</function>-->
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>ulpDouble</name>
    <description>Returns the size of an ulp of the argument. An ulp of a double value is the positive distance between this floating-point value and the double value next larger in magnitude. Note that for non-NaN x, ulp(-x) == ulp(x).
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double ulp(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>ulpFloat</name>
    <description>Returns the size of an ulp of the argument. An ulp of a float value is the positive distance between this floating-point value and the float value next larger in magnitude. Note that for non-NaN x, ulp(-x) == ulp(x).
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>float ulp(float)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>sinh</name>
    <description>Returns the hyperbolic sine of a double value. The hyperbolic sine of x is defined to be (ex - e-x)/2 where e is Euler's number.

    Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN, then the result is NaN.
        If the argument is infinite, then the result is an infinity with the same sign as the argument.
        If the argument is zero, then the result is a zero with the same sign as the argument. 

    The computed result must be within 2.5 ulps of the exact result.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double sinh(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>cosh</name>
    <description>Returns the hyperbolic cosine of a double value. The hyperbolic cosine of x is defined to be (ex + e-x)/2 where e is Euler's number.

    Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN, then the result is NaN.
        If the argument is infinite, then the result is positive infinity.
        If the argument is zero, then the result is 1.0. 

    The computed result must be within 2.5 ulps of the exact result.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double cosh(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>tanh</name>
    <description>Returns the hyperbolic tangent of a double value. The hyperbolic tangent of x is defined to be (ex - e-x)/(ex + e-x), in other words, sinh(x)/cosh(x). Note that the absolute value of the exact tanh is always less than 1.

    Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN, then the result is NaN.
        If the argument is zero, then the result is a zero with the same sign as the argument.
        If the argument is positive infinity, then the result is +1.0.
        If the argument is negative infinity, then the result is -1.0. 

    The computed result must be within 2.5 ulps of the exact result. The result of tanh for any finite input must have an absolute value less than or equal to 1. Note that once the exact result of tanh is within 1/2 of an ulp of the limit value of ±1, correctly signed ±1.0 should be returned.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double tanh(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>hypot</name>
    <description>Returns sqrt(x2 +y2) without intermediate overflow or underflow.

    Special cases:

        If either argument is infinite, then the result is positive infinity.
        If either argument is NaN and neither argument is infinite, then the result is NaN. 

    The computed result must be within 1 ulp of the exact result. If one parameter is held constant, the results must be semi-monotonic in the other parameter.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double hypot(double,double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>expm1</name>
    <description>Returns ex -1. Note that for values of x near 0, the exact sum of expm1(x) + 1 is much closer to the true result of ex than exp(x).

    Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN, the result is NaN.
        If the argument is positive infinity, then the result is positive infinity.
        If the argument is negative infinity, then the result is -1.0.
        If the argument is zero, then the result is a zero with the same sign as the argument. 

    The computed result must be within 1 ulp of the exact result. Results must be semi-monotonic. The result of expm1 for any finite input must be greater than or equal to -1.0. Note that once the exact result of ex - 1 is within 1/2 ulp of the limit value -1, -1.0 should be returned.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double expm1(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>log1p</name>
    <description>Returns the natural logarithm of the sum of the argument and 1. Note that for small values x, the result of log1p(x) is much closer to the true result of ln(1 + x) than the floating-point evaluation of log(1.0+x).

    Special cases:

        If the argument is NaN or less than -1, then the result is NaN.
        If the argument is positive infinity, then the result is positive infinity.
        If the argument is negative one, then the result is negative infinity.
        If the argument is zero, then the result is a zero with the same sign as the argument. 

    The computed result must be within 1 ulp of the exact result. Results must be semi-monotonic.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double log1p(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>copySignFloat</name>
    <description>Returns the first floating-point argument with the sign of the second floating-point argument. Note that unlike the StrictMath.copySign method, this method does not require NaN sign arguments to be treated as positive values; implementations are permitted to treat some NaN arguments as positive and other NaN arguments as negative to allow greater performance.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>float copySign(float,float)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>copySignDouble</name>
    <description>Returns the first floating-point argument with the sign of the second floating-point argument. Note that unlike the StrictMath.copySign method, this method does not require NaN sign arguments to be treated as positive values; implementations are permitted to treat some NaN arguments as positive and other NaN arguments as negative to allow greater performance.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double copySign(double,double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>nextAfterDouble</name>
    <description>Returns the floating-point number adjacent to the first argument in the direction of the second argument. If both arguments compare as equal the second argument is returned.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double nextAfter(double,double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>nextAfterFloat</name>
    <description>Returns the floating-point number adjacent to the first argument in the direction of the second argument. If both arguments compare as equal a value equivalent to the second argument is returned.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>float nextAfter(float,double)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>nextUpFloat</name>
    <description>Returns the floating-point value adjacent to f in the direction of positive infinity. This method is semantically equivalent to nextAfter(f, Float.POSITIVE_INFINITY); however, a nextUp implementation may run faster than its equivalent nextAfter call.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>float nextUp(float)</function-signature>
  </function>
  <function>
    <prefix>math</prefix>
    <name>nextUpDouble</name>
    <description>Returns the floating-point value adjacent to d in the direction of positive infinity. This method is semantically equivalent to nextAfter(d, Double.POSITIVE_INFINITY); however, a nextUp implementation may run faster than its equivalent nextAfter call.
    </description>
    <function-class>java.lang.Math</function-class>
    <function-signature>double nextUp(double)</function-signature>
  </function>
</functions>